{
    "question": "Buatkan teks horatory tentang menanam pohon\u00a0",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "Horatori : tema : argumentasi : saran<br><br>Planting a tree is one of the effort that we can do to make a better air quality. This is due to the ability of tree and its leaves in transforming carbon dioxide into oxygen. Therefore it is highly recommended to start plant a tree at least in our backyard.\u00a0",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "bagaimanakah-penggunaan-kata-either-720",
            "question": "Bagaimanakah penggunaan kata 'either'?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<span>untuk 2 kalimat yang sama-sama negative (-). Contoh dengan<span> (tenses 1) simple present tense, menggunakan </span></span><span><span>katakerja be (am, are is) dengan </span>katasifat (adjective) fine /fain/ = baik.</span><br>example:<br>you are not fine and i am not, either<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "untuk 2 kalimat sama-sama negative dengan menggunakan kata kerja be(am,are,is)<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "terdiri-dari-apa-sajakah-causative-have-itu-798",
            "question": "Terdiri dari apa sajakah causative have itu",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Causative verb menunjukkan bahwa seseorang/sesuatu secara tidak langsung bertanggung jawab terhadap sebuah tindakan. Subjek tidak melakukan tindakan itu sendiri, tetapi justru menyebabkan seseorang/sesuatu yang lain melakukannya. Contoh:<br>- Yesterday I had my hair cut.<br>Pembicara pada kalimat diatas tidak memotong sendiri rambutnya, tetapi justru membuat orang lain melakukannya \u2013 Saya \u201cmenyebabkan\u201d mereka memotong rambut saya.<br>Have<br>Have merupakan causative verb yang umum. Ketimbang melakukan sesuatu dengan diri kita sendiri, kita \u201cmenyuruh\u201d orang yang lain untuk melakukannya. Bentuknya sebagai berikut:<br>Kata kerja \u201cto have\u201d + objek + past participle (verb 3). Contoh:<br>- I had my jacket cleaned yesterday.<br>- Did you have your computer fixed?<br>Terkadang kita menggunakan have sebagai causative verb ketika kita ingin melakukan tindakan oleh diri kita sendiri. Contoh:<br>- When will the report be ready? I\u2019ll do it by tomorrow morning. &gt;&gt;<br>- When will the report be ready? I\u2019ll have it done by tomorrow morning.<br>Dengan menggunakan causative, kalimat ke-dua diatas mengalihkan perhatian dari pelaku tindakan, dan lebih memberikan perhatian kepada tindakan yang sedang dilakukan. Ini kedengaran sopan dan profesional.<br>Get<br>Get sering digunakan ketimbang have. Contoh:<br>\u2022\tI got my computer fixed \u2013 I had my computer fixed. Kedua kalimat ini maknanya sama.<br>\u2022\tI got my jacket cleaned. \u2013 I had my jacket cleaned. Kedua kalimat ini maknanya sama.<br>Causative verbs sering digunakan bersama dengan pengalaman-pengalaman negatif. Pada situasi-situasi ini lebih umum menggunakan have. Contoh:<br>\u2022\tI had my wallet stolen. (Saya sebenarnya tidak menyebabkan dompet saya dicuri \u2013 seseorang mencuri dompet saya dariku)<br><span>\u2022\tShe had her window smashed.<br><br></span>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-percakapan-expression-care-826",
            "question": "Contoh percakapan expression care",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "how poor you are<br>what a pity<br>i am sorry to hear that",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Situation : Your friend is sad.<br><br>Ana : <strong>Are you okay? You look so sad.</strong><br>Nia : <em>No, I&#039;m not okay.</em> I feel so sad because I had a fight with my brother yesterday.<br>Ana : Why?<br>Nia : He took my favorite novel without asking my permission and he ripped it! How can I not sad? He even not sorry at all and when I yelled at him, he yelled me back with his ridiculous reason that why should I got sad over a novel!<br>Ana : You must be really hurt...<br>Nia : Of couse I do.<br>Ana : <strong>What should I do to cheer you up?</strong><br>Nia : <em>Thanks for your attention</em> but no, sorry.<br>Ana : <strong>Really?</strong> I&#039;m sorry I can&#039;t help you much.<br>Nia: <em>Yeah, thanks</em>.<br><br><strong>bold: expressions<br></strong><em>italic: responses</em><strong><br></strong>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-text-spoof-pake-twist-falling-into-a-well-dong-306",
            "question": "Contoh text SPOOF pake twist \"falling into a well\" dong :)",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<span>\nSpoof text: Falling Into a Well</span>\n<span>\n</span>\n\nThere was a man. When he was walking, he fell into a well.\n<span>\n<br></span>\n\nMany people saw the incident so they came to save him. Unfortunately no \none could enter the well to bring him out. Later, a smart man came up \nwith a bright idea to throw the man a strong rope to try to pull him out\n the well.\n<span>\n<br></span>\n\nWhen the rope reached\u00a0 and hit the man\u2019s head, he shouted angrily: \u201cDon&#039; bother me! Pick your own well, I am bathing.\u201d\n<br>\n\nDo you get the point why that short passage can be labeled as a spoof \ntext? Before we are going to go further, Let&#039;s see its rough translation\n to help you to\u00a0 get better understanding\n<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-perbedaan-antara-simple-past-tense-dengan-present-perfect-ten-100",
            "question": "Apa perbedaan antara simple past tense dengan present perfect tense ?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Simple pastanse untuk menyatakan kejadian yang sudah lalu<br>present perfect untuk menyatakan kejadian yang direncanakan",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "simple past tense dipakai saat keterangan waktunya sudah selesai, \nsedangkan present perfect dipakai saat keterangan waktunya belum \nselesai/masih berlanjut.<br>Contoh:<br>I bought 3 books last week. (simple past-last week sudah berlalu)<br>I have bought 3 books this week. (present perfect-this week belum berlalu, masih berlangsung)<br><br>present perfect menggunakan &#039;for&#039; dan &#039;since&#039; saat kegiatannya masih berlanjut.<br><br>I have lived in London for 3 years. (present perfect-masih berlangsung, sekarang pun masih di London)<br>I have lived in London since 1990. (sampai sekarang masih tinggal di London)\n<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-bedanya-conditional-type-1-2-dan-3-320",
            "question": "Apa bedanya conditional type 1, 2 dan 3 ???",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "if conditional sentences? beda tenses-nya, sama fact-nya",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Type 1 = Real / Present Conditional (terjadi sekarang)<br>Form = If + S + V1..., I + will + V1...<br>Example = If I have money, I will treat you<br>Meaning = it may/ may not happen. Jadi artinya bisa terjadi atau tidak.<br><br>Type 2 = Contrary to the present fact (bertentangan sama yang terjadi pada kenyataan)<br>Form = If + S + V2..., I + would + V1...<br>Example = <br>a. If I <u>had money,</u> I would treat you<br>b. If I <u>were</u> you, I would leave him<br>Meaning = <br>a1. I don&#039;t <u>have money</u>, so I dont treat you, or<br>a2. I don&#039;t treat you, because I don&#039;t have money<br>b. I<u>&#039;m</u> not you, so I don&#039;t leave him<br>(intinya kalau conditional 2, penyataan dalam v2, arti dalam v1)<br><br>Type 3 <br>Form = If + S + had + V3..., I + would + have + V3...<br>Example = <br>a. If I had had money, I would have treated you<br>b. If my father had got marred again, my mother would have killed him<br>Meaning = <br>a. I didn&#039;t have money, so I didn&#039;t treat you<br>b. My father didn&#039;t get married again, so my mother didn&#039;t kill him<br>(intinya kalau conditional 3, penyataan dalam v3, arti dalam v2)<br><br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "there-care-many-reasons-for-keeping-dogs-as-pete-in-the-city-area-554",
            "question": "There care many reasons for keeping dogs as Pete in the city area, but many peo- ple feel that keeping pet dogs should not be allowed In the city. Dogs are often not taken care properly. They are kept in small backyards and rarely taken for walks. They are left in the yard all day by themselves while the family rune work. Very little attention is given to the dog and it is not a very good life for it. It is no wonder why these dogs bark and disturb the neighbours and become a nuisance to the community.\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0 On the other hand, not all people treat their dogs this may and why should the peo- ple receive a lot of pleasure and enjoyment from dog's stifle'? Dogs can make a lonely person's life happy or make wonderful play- mate. It can also teach a child responsibility as they not only Potts lay with the dog, but also need to exercise, feed, and care for the dog.\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0 I feel that we should be allowed to keep dogs in the city, because ills is taken care of properly, dogs can be a great source of pleasure. As a child / used to enjoy playing and taking care of my pet. There is not greater loyalty a nelson can get than from a well-caned dog.\u00a0    1. Some people do not like the presence of pet dogs In their surroundings because ....\u00a0\u00a0 \r\n(A) the dogs are left in the yards\u00a0 \r\n(B) the dogs are often neglected \r\n(C) the dogs often bark and disturb the neighbours \r\n(D) the dogs play with the owner's child \r\n(E) the dogs guard the security of the enyit onrnent\u00a0 \r\n\r\n2. The main idea of the last paragraph is ....\u00a0\u00a0 \r\n(A) pet dogs are loyal animals \r\n(B) pet dogs are more loyal than humans \r\n(C) dogs can be a great source of pleasure \r\n(D) the writer has no objection to keeping dogs In the city \r\n(E) the writer used to play and took care of his pet when he was a child\u00a0 \r\n\r\n3. We can infer from the text that keeping pet dogs in the city will not cause any problem as long ....\u00a0\u00a0 \r\n(A) the dogs are amusing \r\n(B) the neighbours like having pet dogs \r\n(C) the dogs do not balk at the neighbours \r\n(D) the writer has succeeded in persuading the neighbours \r\n(E) its presence does not disturb the neighbourhood",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "1.c.the dogs often bark and disturb the neighbours<br>2.c.dogs can be a great source of pleasure<br>3.e.it&#039;s presence does not disturb the neighbourhood<br>ini menurut jawaban saya :)",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-jelaskan-secara-singkat-dan-jelas-pengertian-dari-report-t-269",
            "question": "Tolong jelaskan secara singkat dan jelas pengertian dari report teks",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Definition of Report<br>Report is a text which presents information about something, as it is. It is as a result of systematic observation and analysis<br><br>Generic Structure of Report<br>1. General classification: Stating classification of general aspect of thing; animal, public place, plant, etc which will be discussed in general<br>2. Description: Describing the thing which will be discussed in detail; part per part , customs or deed for living creature and usage for materials<br><br>Language Feature of Report<br>\u2022 Introducing group or general aspect<br>\u2022 Using conditional logical connection; when, so, etc<br><span>\u2022 Using simple present tense</span>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "report text adalah salah satu jenis teks yang masuk kategori \" factual text \"<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "bantuin-aku-dong-cari-biografi-aknes-monica-menggunakan-bahasa-in-292",
            "question": "Bantuin aku dong cari Biografi aknes monica menggunakan Bahasa inggris",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Agnes Monica Muljoto. Born in Jakarta 1 July 1986, known abroad as Agnes Mo. She stared her career in the entertainment industry at the age of six as a child singer. She jobs is singer, actress, dancer, voice actress, and producer.",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-dialog-expression-suggestion-170",
            "question": "Contoh dialog expression suggestion?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "I have been usiung asparagus extract ( 2capsules per day in the morning ) on the suggestion of my doctor who is aDO.<br>This has helped reduce the amount of fluid retention. Seacoast vitamins has consistently had the lowest price for the same brand I was buying at the heralthfood store.",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}